<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <channel> <title>Charles Xu</title> <description>Essays, books, wiki on technologies, career, markets, and more.</description> <link>/</link> <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/> <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 01:38:57 -0500</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 01:38:57 -0500</lastBuildDate> <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator> <item> <title>Enterprise Sales</title> <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-do-product-led-growth-and-hands-on-outbound-sales-at-the-same-time&quot;&gt;How to do product-led growth and hands-on outbound sales at the same time?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every PLG company eventually has to embrace enterprise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Annie Pearl, Chef Product Officer at Calendly&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The upper limit of PLG seems to be $100M to $200M ARR (e.g. DataDog around IPO). Beyond triple-digit million ARR, you quickly saturate the market of users who buy things by pulling out their credit cards. The growth of the PLG channel naturally slows at some point. &lt;!-- As you expend from selling to individuals/teams to selling to cross-functional organizations, you need t --&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most companies start with self-serve PLG and then layer in enterprise sales. This may not work well. Your entry-level product could cannibalize your enterprise product. &lt;mark&gt;Think hard about differentiation that justifies the premium. &lt;/mark&gt; You cannot just add single-sign-on (SSO) and call it enterprise edition.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some common enterprise features are:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;thead&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/thead&gt; &lt;tbody&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Customer supports&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Support is what makes or breaks the enterprise product. Your company success is defined solely by customer success. 24/7 or business hours? Email, chat, or phone support? SLA on response time?&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Dedicated account manager&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Evangelize best practices and champion support.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Fine-grain authorization policy&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Roles and permissions.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Audit logs&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;User and workload identity, actions, timestamp, easy export.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Compliance&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;For example, FedRAMP, HIPAA, GDPR, SOC2.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;High availability&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;For example, multi-region disaster recovery, cross-region replication, four-nine uptime SLA.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Private network&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Private link, VPC peering, single-tenant deployment.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Self-host&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;User-managed private deployment&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Data retention period&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;For example, DataDog allows free accounts to view metrics from last 24h&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;For example, run the same pytorch model 100x faster.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tbody&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another pro tip: &lt;mark&gt;within minutes of self-serve signups, directly reach out to that new user&lt;/mark&gt;, assuming they pass certain criteria about company size and title. The reason is, your product is top of mind for the user right now, who clearly has been doing research about this space. If they give you the phone number, call them directly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;when-to-layer-in-enterprise-sales&quot;&gt;When to layer in enterprise sales?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Similarly, when to make the first sales hire?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You need product-market fit (PMF) and annual recurring revenue (ARR). PMF is shown through retention, exponential and organic customer growth, and net promoter score (NPS, or how upset would you be if this product disappears? How likely would you recommend this product to your friends?). To learn more about PMF, I love this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-know-if-youve-got-productmarket&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; by Lenny Rachitsky.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rule of thumb: you need at least $1M ARR to show you can sell outside of your network (friends and family).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;should-your-first-sales-hire-be-head-of-sales-or-junior-sales-rep&quot;&gt;Should your first sales hire be head of sales or junior sales rep?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;You probably don’t yet need a head of sales because&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;The target customers and the deal size remain uncertain, so it is hard to know if a candidate is the right person.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Head of sales is expensive and often commands a structure in marketing, finance, legal, etc. Big overhead.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Head of sales probably has not been down in the weeds for a while.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;You should not hire anyone junior because it takes your time to train them, such as how to write emails and pricing proposal.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;An ideal candidate would be an account executive (AE) at a hypergrowth company with great track record, or someone recently moved into front-line management who used to be an AE and who desires the opportunity to grow into the head of sales role.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some revealing questions to ask:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Tell me about a deal that you lost.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Let’s do a mock discovery call together.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Out of the 8 SDRs on your team, where did you come up on the leaderboard? What are the folks front-running you doing differently?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;when-do-you-start-outbound&quot;&gt;When do you start outbound?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to Maggie Hott, Director of Sales at Webflow, &lt;mark&gt;the answer is always now. The goal of cold outbound is not to close deals but to build brand awareness and educate potential customers&lt;/mark&gt;. You almost never hit the prospects at the right time, but when they are ready to buy, prior outbounds make you part of the evaluation. Whereas marketing targets a market segment, outbounds are personalized to each prospect.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Maggie recommends a 10-80-10 outbound strategy:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;First 10% is personalized and explains how the prospect could relate to your product. &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;For example, “Hey John, amazing talk at KubeCon last week with such great lessons for multi-cloud adoption. I am curious how your team approaches multi-cloud observability and cost attribution. All the folks I talked to are struggling with this. I think our product can really help.”&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Mid 80% is repeatable product marketing.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Last 10% is to ask for that call or meeting, and end with a playful closing.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lauren Schwartz, VP of Sales at Fivetran, stressed the importance of having multiple sponsors in the prospect’s organization. People change jobs and have different types of influence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;should-we-give-discounts-for-testimonials&quot;&gt;Should we give discounts for testimonials?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the early days, &lt;mark&gt;worry less about the contract size but focus on getting those logos&lt;/mark&gt;. The bulk of the enterprise market is the early majority and late majority. They are almost never early adopters. They need testimony and success stories.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Maybe you could get more testimonials through discounts, but be judicious about discounts, because people talk, and soon more customers will ask for discounts. &lt;mark&gt;The best reason to give discounts is to control the close date and payment structure of the deal&lt;/mark&gt;. You can always bring up the ask for testimonials if the prospect comes back asking for more discounts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- Frank: don&apos;t have CS team. / Add notes from Annie Pearl --&gt; </description> <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate> <link>/sales-lessons/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/sales-lessons/</guid> <category>sales</category> <category>startup</category> <category>advice</category> </item> <item> <title>More Career Advices</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It has been a few years since my previous post &lt;a href=&quot;/advices/&quot;&gt;Advices I wish I got at the start of my career&lt;/a&gt;. Here is some more career advices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-for-help&quot;&gt;Ask for help&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Son, your ego is writing checks your body can’t cash.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Captain Tom “Stinger” Jordan, Top Gun&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The number one reason why senior people fail is that they do not ask for help. We are all shareholders. You do whatever you can to unblock yourself. It is about time to market and showing results.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;promote-thought-leadership&quot;&gt;Promote thought leadership&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you want to build a ship, don’t drum up the men to gather wood, divide the work and give orders. Instead, teach them to yearn for the vast and endless sea.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Antoine de Saint-Exupery, author of The Little Prince&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;In tech, most decisions are based on influence, not hierarchy. Thought leadership is a great way to gain influence. To be a leader, you should start by acting like one. Be confident, give tech talks, and voice your opinions in planning, design review, and postmortems. Doing so makes you the obvious choice for the next big project or the next leadership roles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The outcome and how you drove that outcome are both important. Be careful with your reputation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;befriend-jeff-bezos-before-he-gets-rich&quot;&gt;Befriend Jeff Bezos before he gets rich&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The best time to become friends with Jeff Bezos is before he becomes rich and famous. Networking does not mean you must reach upward. Invest in your peers, who are more receptive to getting to know you. Imagine you are Stripe in 2012. Rather than running into walls with F500 enterprises, you should onboard hundreds of startups, because among them are the next Airbnb and Lyft. Relationships compound. Start early.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do informational interviews. Ask people at other firms what they like and don’t like about their job. Always follow up to maintain weak ties, such as&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Saying hello to someone you met at a conference last year. Or asking if they’ll be attending after this year’s agenda is published.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Share interesting news about your old company with a former colleague.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Send them news, event, commentary related to their interests. Examples: &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;“Tom, I just read this great white paper on blockchain. I know you’d get a lot out of this.”&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;“Alice, congrats on the new job. Enclosed please find a copy of the best book I’ve read on starting a new job, The First 90 Days. Call me if you want to compare notes.”&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;“James, I just got an invite to a private class at this new gym but can’t go. You mentioned you love Crossfit — want my ticket?”&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;stop-productivity-porn-bias-towards-action&quot;&gt;Stop productivity porn. Bias towards action.&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Watching others lifting weights is not going to make you fit. Many of us spend so much time collecting books we want to read but haven’t, or studying how others slice up their days to get more done. You get more done by doing and by starting now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;develope-relationship-skills&quot;&gt;Develope relationship skills&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;A major reason change efforts so often fail is that successful implementation eventually requires people to have difficult conversations … With everyone taking for granted that their own view is right, and readily assuming that others’ opposition is self-interested, progress quickly grinds to a halt. Decisions are delayed, and when finally made they are often imposed without buy-in from those who have to implement them. Relationships sour. Eventually people give up in frustration, and those driving the effort get distracted by new challenges or the next next big thing. The ability to manage difficult conversations effectively is foundational, then, to achieving almost any significant change.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Douglas Stone, Author of “Difficult Conversations: How to Discuss What Matters”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Relationship problems are at the heart of every organization. Take product managers (PM) and engineering managers (EM) for example. PM &amp;amp; EM have overlapping scopes by definition. When you seek better scoping, you don’t have a scoping problem, you have a relationship problem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are some tips:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be a good listener&lt;/strong&gt;. People rarely change. People just want to be understood. Listening is more persuasive than talking. Listening fosters a reciprocal relationship. Listening is not just about paraphrasing back. Ask deep and relevant questions, take notes, and maintain eye contact. For many, listening needs to be a trained response. When you are frustrated, you are the least curious—you have so much noise in your internal head that left little space to worry about what’s on the other person’s head. Learn to lean into the conflicts, just like firefighters learn to run towards the fire.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lean into conflicts&lt;/strong&gt;. Avoiding conflict is the worst kind of measure of relationship health. Staying quiet creates resentment. You must confront, but do so with skills and preparation. It is mature to share your feeling and inquire about others’. Doing so builds trust. For example: “Bob, I feel frustrated. It seems this conversation is not getting anywhere, and I want to understand why.” Acknowledge the differences between the two parties, not who is right or better. I love this example “Jill, you and I seem to have different preferences about when code reviews should be done. I wonder if that’s something we could talk about?”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolve email conflicts in person&lt;/strong&gt;. If a conflict starts on email, it is hard to solve on email. In this case, just meet in person or pick up the phone. It is hard to communicate emotions through email—no tone, no voice, no facial expression, no body language.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apology diffuses the tension&lt;/strong&gt;. In most conflicts, blaming does not help. Most of the time, you share part of the blame, even just 5%. Apologizing and acknowledging the fault on your side could really diffuse the tension. Apology is an underrated and underutilized skill. Apology needs to be genuine. Saying “I am sorry that you feel that way” is not genuine. Here is how to make a good apology:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;Acknowledge the harm. “I am sorry that I interrupted you in the meeting.”&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Say why it is wrong. “It was disrespectful and discourage the full exchange of ideas.”&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Say what you &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; do next time, not what you won’t do. “I will make sure to let you finish before I chime in.”&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Ask for forgiveness. Bring cupcakes.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;go-straight-to-the-job-you-want&quot;&gt;Go straight to the job you want&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don’t let inertia drive you. Take some risks when you are young. No one in their 40s said they took too much risk.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you are unhappy about your job, move on. Every job change you make, you always wish you make it 6 months earlier. Life is so short. Do not spend time on jobs that you do not like. You will be so productive in jobs you like. Don’t assume that you have to do this job, then get that job and then that job, and then you can do what you really want. Go direct.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Know your alternative. Negotiate hard on your second best offer, then negotiate with your first choice, knowing what you can walk away towards. Pay attention to details. Be specific about equity grant date, vesting schedule, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;what-to-look-for-in-the-next-job-growth&quot;&gt;What to look for in the next job: Growth&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the right opportunities, you can 10x your impact every decade. Because of compounding, what seems to be golden handcuffs today is dwarfed by the opportunity to accelerate growth. The exponential curve actually consists of many little S-curves. If you find yourself approaching the flattening end of the S-curve, it is time for a change.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate> <link>/more-advices/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/more-advices/</guid> <category>career</category> </item> <item> <title>Interviewing Adrien Treuille, Founder CEO of Streamlit</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Streamlit, about to raise its Series-C, was acquired by Snowflake for $800M in March 2022. In this conversation with Adrien, we chatted about OSS metrics, licenses, open-core vs freemium vs free trial, PLG vs sales motion, third party contributions, and lessons from building Streamlit. Insights belong to Adrien. Errors and omissions are my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;given-streamlit-is-an-open-source-product-what-are-the-most-important-metrics-you-watch-for-while-you-build-this-product-why&quot;&gt;Given Streamlit is an open-source product, what are the most important metrics you watch for while you build this product? Why?&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Open-source telemetry is a gray area in the open-source world. Because the things that you’d like to track are typically not the things that like open-source projects are supposed to track like utilization. There are two kinds of utilization metrics:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indirect measure of utilization&lt;/strong&gt;: downloads, GitHub stars, and engagement metrics on forums (slack, stackoverflow). &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Direct measure of utilization&lt;/strong&gt;: which features were used when. This is a SaaS-like approach, people don’t always like this&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Streamlit did the latter. We made it very clear when you install Streamlit that we’re going to collect the statistics, and here’s how you turn off the data collection. We wanted to be good citizens in that regard. This opt-out feature means we may not be aware of all utilization patterns. Conversely, we were able to better visibility into the Streamlit community, such as the monthly active developers and viewers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Active users are trailing metrics, not leading metrics. They don’t really inform product decisions but are a overall score. You brought up a good point about these metrics are more common in consumer software. Streamlit may consider itself as a B2D company, D as in developers. B2D is not too different from B2C, so I want to optimize for virality and engagement. Taking some members of the community and making them famous is a really key strategy. We were doing all that stuff like crazy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-considered-freemium-or-free-trial-what-makes-open-source-a-better-fit-for-streamlit&quot;&gt;Have you considered freemium or free trial? What makes open source a better fit for Streamlit?&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you target an existing workload at companies, focus on exactly that customer set, make them as happy as possible, do better than the competition, and you might not have to open source. HEX is an example, which is saying like, hey, we’re gonna make this about notebook, but it’s like super annoying, so we’re going to improve on it in like, six, seven ways.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, for Streamlit, it was clear that we were inventing a new workload. Early adopters were usually groups working on super high-tech things that like they themselves, their processes were so wide open that they could determine everything we fashion and instrument to work perfectly. These early adopters convinced me to start a company. For example, Uber was using Streamlit to figure out where to put chargers for the electric bikes. If you’re inventing new workloads, then the strategy is you have to become universal, we just had to open source.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Charles: It’s a very similar approach, especially in the infrastructure world, where you really have to be the de facto standard. Thus, you need to earn users’ trust so they’re willing to invest in this platform to get the kind of snowball effect rolling.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Adrien: Exactly. It’s all like famous for being famous.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;streamlit-uses-an-apache2-license-have-you-considered-mongodb-and-elastics-licensing-model-why-not&quot;&gt;Streamlit uses an Apache2 license. Have you considered MongoDB and Elastic’s licensing model? Why not?&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;We could always transition to a model like that. Mongo is an example of a company that changed licenses. But the truth is that we never really got to a point where the Apache2 license was an issue, as we were out there trying to win the community. We did in some ways pull away from the pack of people who were doing similar things two or three years ago.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our next big challenge was to monetize. We had a theory for how to do so, though it was certainly not proven. We were literally onboarding our first paying customers, when snowflake approached us for acquisition. And we said no actually, because we had great term sheets from amazing investors and we had the revenue. Snowflake said, we don’t want you to figure out how to make money, because if you do, you’re gonna get way too expensive. Snowflake matched our term sheet valuation and went over a bit to catch the projected revenue. The term sheet we had was to raise $95 million, which buys years of runways, so we would have figured out the business problems along the way.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;is-it-possible-to-do-both-plg-and-sales-motion-at-the-same-time&quot;&gt;Is it possible to do both PLG and sales motion at the same time?&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Charles: Integration is always a challenge with any acquisition. Specifically, Streamlit started as an open-source project, and it’s about to get into monetization with product lead growth, which is different from snowflake’s sales-driven model. How do we best integrate the two products together?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Adrien: The quick answer is yes. The question is, what does that actually look like?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think what it looks like is perhaps less PLG. For me, true PLG looks like this: we’re gonna convince you to pay up like $1,000 a year for us, and then before you know it, you’ll be paying like a million dollars a year for us because we’re just gonna prove our worth to the entire organization and the adoption growth is bottom-up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our ambition at snowflake is not to turn Snowflake sales motion into a PLG motion but to piggyback on snowflake’s unbelievably successful sales motion. What we can be is beloved by developers and be a reason why a deal cuts in Snowflake direction. This is the lower ambition. The higher ambition is the above plus driving a ton of credit consumption and indulgence. Snowflake and Streamlit have a lot of joint users. If the next prospect, who is doing diligence on Snowflake, asks internally that Snowflake comes with this Streamlit thing, who has heard of it? And the data science teams all say that would be awesome. This totally goes for snowflake, right? And then all of a sudden, a massive workload moves over to snowflake. That is success. Whether you call it PLG or not, I think it’s completely compatible with Snowflake’s sales motion.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;how-do-you-prioritize-community-feature-requests-vs-your-product-roadmap-what-to-do-with-voluntary-and-unsolicited-contributions&quot;&gt;How do you prioritize community feature requests vs your product roadmap? What to do with voluntary and unsolicited contributions?&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Charles: I have this question because I get common feedback from open-source maintainers that contributions from individual community members are great, but once we accept their contributions, we have to maintain the features going forward in all future releases. By then the original contributors are gone. However, rejecting their contributions would be such a blow to their love of your products. Would you prioritize differently based on the feedback and contributions you got?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Adrien: The good news about your story about the contributor release is that in practice, it never works that way. For all the serious open-source projects that I know of, there are no nontrivial yet drive-by contributions. The actual so-called community contributions are more things like adding a comma in README. For Streamlit, if someone wants to merge a fundamentally new feature that lets you, for example, parse URL parameters and do whatever, we would just take a look at it and say no, because it was not in our roadmap, and it wasn’t the way we would have done it. We are not gonna let people check random things into Streamlit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But, the thing that the community does do extremely well, which is kind of evergreen in its own way, is to provide a ton of IP around the project. For example, every StackOverflow answer and every example code in the public repos. GitHub Copilot writes fantastic Streamlit code, which is amazing. You can literally add a comment like show Yahoo stock pricing stream, and Copilot popped out a beautiful app. All those are community contributions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;what-remains-the-biggest-challenge-in-data-infra&quot;&gt;What remains the biggest challenge in data infra?&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Streamlit is just like one piece of a huge ecosystem of data infrastructure, all of which is changing really quickly. Whether snowflake keeps up with and leaves the pack is a question that far transcends Streamlit. We are just going to play a role in a positive direction. In many ways, the promise is still ahead of us, in the sense that the actual number of companies—that are really committed to using us and have like amazing results—wasn’t that big, but those that did got really solid results. The challenge is replicating that experience, like 10x 100x 1000x.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;if-you-were-to-start-streamlit-again-what-would-you-do-differently&quot;&gt;If you were to start Streamlit again, what would you do differently?&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;The biggest mistake I had was not hiring leaders fast enough and growing the organization’s maturity. I was worried that a hiring mistake could backfire for us, but in reality, the executives we hired worked out extremely well. When I interviewed them, I wished I had met them sooner because they could truly bring lots of value to the team. They really increased the execution velocity by making the organization scalable.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate> <link>/streamlit-interview/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/streamlit-interview/</guid> <category>oss</category> <category>interview</category> <category>startup</category> </item> <item> <title>Kubernetes Networking From the First Principles</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;We go from containers and network namespace to Pod-to-Pod, Pod-to-Service, and external-client-to-Service networking.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;pods&quot;&gt;Pods&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Containers of the same Pod share the same Linux network namespace, isolated from the host network namespace.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Each Pod gets a separate network namespace and is assigned a cluster-wide unique IP address from the cluster’s Pod CIDR range. Many managed Kubernetes offerings use Host-local IPAM (IP Address Management), so that each Node is fist assigned a subnet of Pod CIDR. Then, each Pod gets its IP address from the Node the Pod is on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Kubernetes networking model requires that a container in Pod A can reach a container in Pod B, crossing network namespaces, regardless of whether Pods A and B are on the same Node or not.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;pod-to-pod-on-the-same-node&quot;&gt;Pod to Pod on the same Node&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;For each Pod, kubelet will create a VETH (Virtual Ethernet Device) pair in the host network namespace. Packets transmitted on one device in the pair are immediately received on the other device. Then Kubelet will move one device of such pair into the Pod’s network namespace and rename this device to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;eth0&lt;/code&gt; in the Pod’s namespace. Each VETH device remained in the host network namespace will be assigned a Pod IP and be connected to a software bridge &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cbr0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/k8s-net/p1.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;pod-to-pod-on-another-node&quot;&gt;Pod to Pod on another Node&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/k8s-net/p2.png&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;On &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Node-1&lt;/code&gt;, IP packets (whose source and destination addresses are the Pod IPs) sent by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-1&lt;/code&gt; will be encapsulated as Ethernet frames being sent to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cbr0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cbr0&lt;/code&gt; switch has a match-all forwarding rule for all packets destinated to anything but &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Node-1&lt;/code&gt;’s subnet of Pod CIDR. The CNI plugin in VXLAN mode will encapsulate the Ethernet frames as UDP packets. These UDP packets’ source and destination addresses are the Node IPs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;clusterip-type-services&quot;&gt;ClusterIP-type Services&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Even though Pod IPs are routable, Pods (and hence the Pod IPs) are ephemeral by design. Hence, it is more reliable and recommended to use the Kubernetes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Service&lt;/code&gt;, which provides a static cluster IP and load balancing over a group of Pods. The most basic Service type is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ClusterIP&lt;/code&gt;, which represents a service available within the cluster but not exposed to the internet.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;ClusterIP-type Services are implemented using kube-proxy, which is not a real proxy (data plane) but configures iptables to capture and NAT traffic to cluster IP of the Service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Below is an example of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-1&lt;/code&gt; sending a request to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;service-1&lt;/code&gt; backed by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-0&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-2&lt;/code&gt;. Encapsulation details covered in the previous section are omitted from the diagram below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/k8s-net/p3.png&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Kube-proxy will choose at random one of the backing Pods to serve the request, by dNATing the destination IP from the Service’s cluster IP to the IP of the chosen Pod, which in this example is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-2&lt;/code&gt;. Note that the response from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-2&lt;/code&gt; will be sNATed back to the Service’s cluster IP, so that kube-proxy remains transparent to workloads. Otherwise, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-1&lt;/code&gt; only has connection states about &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;service-1&lt;/code&gt;, not &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-2&lt;/code&gt;, and thus will reset the connection.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;nodeport-type-services&quot;&gt;NodePort-type Services&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;To expose a service to clients outside of the cluster, use the NodePort-type Service, which reserves the same port on each Node such that the client could access the service by hitting the NodePort on any Nodes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The example below assumes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;externalTrafficPolicy&lt;/code&gt; is set to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cluster&lt;/code&gt;, which means traffic can be routed to a backing Pod on a different Node. Here, the cluster-external client send requests to the NodePort of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;service-1&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Node-0&lt;/code&gt;, and kube-proxy chooses &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-2&lt;/code&gt; to serve the request.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/k8s-net/p4.png&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Obviously the destination address will be masqueraded from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Node-0&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-2&lt;/code&gt;, but notice that source address is also masqueraded, from the client IP to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Node-0&lt;/code&gt;’s IP. Source-NATing is necessary, because otherwise &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod-2&lt;/code&gt; will respond directly to the client, who assume it is maintaining a connection to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Node-0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate> <link>/k8s-net/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/k8s-net/</guid> <category>kubernetes</category> <category>networking</category> </item> <item> <title>Accounting Advice for Founders</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes derived from a guest lecture by Danny Wallace, Partner at PwC’s Silicon Valley practice. For informational purposes only. Errors and omissions are my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;collect-sales-tax-from-early-on&quot;&gt;Collect sales tax from early on&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/17-494_j4el.pdf&quot;&gt;South Dakota v. Wayfair&lt;/a&gt; supreme court case, businesses without a physical presence in a state but with more than 200 transactions or $100,000 in-state sales should pay sales taxes in the state. Many startups did not collect sales tax at all, a mistake that will defer IPO and M&amp;amp;A deals. Fixing the sales tax issue is expensive for 2 reasons:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;You need to pay sales tax in arrears.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Starting to charge sales tax will hurt your growth numbers and hence valuation.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sales tax is an issue that comes up on every M&amp;amp;A deal. By all means, the company needs to get registered for sales tax and should seek professional advice.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;classify-operating-expenses-cleverly-reduce-ga&quot;&gt;Classify operating expenses cleverly, reduce G&amp;amp;A&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Operating expenses are not created equal. We prefer R&amp;amp;D (research and development), and maybe S&amp;amp;M (sales and marketing), over G&amp;amp;A (general and administrative). Take advantage of the reporting flexibility of expense classification. For example, rent in the Bay Area is high, and some startups put rent under G&amp;amp;A, but we could allocate the rent to different items. Suppose you have one floor for G&amp;amp;A, one floor for R&amp;amp;D, and one floor for S&amp;amp;M, then we can only report a third of the rent under G&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also, there are opportunities to capitalize the R&amp;amp;D expenses so they do not hit the income statement and go straight to the balance sheet and depreciate over time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;do-409a-valuation-every-year-and-proper-tax-withholding&quot;&gt;Do 409a valuation every year and proper tax withholding&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;You must do a 409a valuation at least once a year, which will qualify for a safe harbor for the next 12 months. Otherwise, the IRS may challenge the tax status of the stock rewards to employees, and in turn, employees may sue the company for failure to perform 409a valuation properly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Grant the stock rewards at the fair market value, or there will be tax consequences.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The company needs to issue 1099’s to the contractors. If the company does not, IRS will treat the contractors as employees. As the business expands globally, you also need to consider international taxes and work with professionals to design a global tax strategy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;watch-out-for-internal-fraud&quot;&gt;Watch out for internal fraud&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Especially in the seed and early stages, startups are plagued with internal fraud and misappropriation of the company’s assets. Two-thirds of all US-based small businesses fall victim to employee theft. Common schemes include expensing trips that never took place, claiming personal expenses as business ones, and falsifying sales for commissions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fraud is common at this stage because companies often have no formal processes in place, and operators are too busy with getting the business off the ground. The companies should minimize the number of corporate credit cards and require approvals for all purchases and transfers above a certain threshold. At the same time, strengthen the hiring process with reference checks and background checks. Set up a whistleblower hotline.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;always-verify-communication-with-a-second-means&quot;&gt;Always verify communication with a second means&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;External fraud is also prevalent, with the most common one being phishing emails for wire transfer. Examples of spoofed emails are the CEO asking emergency wire transfer for a confidential deal, or a vendor requesting for updating bank information. Or the hackers may fake a login page to get your internal systems credentials, risking your intellectual property and employee data. Spoofing could also be in physical mails.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You should always verify the intent with a second means, such as calling the alleged sender directly and set up multi-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;think-twice-before-publishing-key-metrics-protect-data-integrity&quot;&gt;Think twice before publishing key metrics, protect data integrity&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Besides items from financial statements, a company may choose to publish key metrics specific to the business, such as monthly active users, number of paying customers, net retention rate, number of completed trips, etc. You need to clearly define and consistently measure the key metrics. Once you publish such metrics, you need to continue doing so going forward. Data integrity and history are crucial. Investors will sue for any misrepresentation of the metrics. Similar to how you should prevent internal fraud, make sure you have internal control in place.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;own-your-revenue-model-ratable-or-non-ratable-net-or-gross&quot;&gt;Own your revenue model: ratable or non-ratable, net or gross&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is a trade-off between the ratable and non-ratable revenue models. Ratable means proportional. Ratable models recognize service revenue over time as services are provided. The revenue schedule is defined in the contract elements. Ratable models are more predictable and offer more visibility into the company. For example, SaaS companies with mouthy subscriptions can provide great guidance to investors with a high degree of confidence. However, ratable models are less tweakable. For example, at the end of the quarter, if you risk missing the forecast numbers, you cannot just send salespeople out to get deals done on the last day of the quarter. Even if you do so, you recognize only one day of revenue.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another dimension of the revenue model is gross vs net, especially for marketplace and platform businesses. For example, Uber follows the net revenue model. If Uber collects $10 from a rider, pays the driver $8, pockets $2, Uber will recognize $2 revenue instead of $10, and $0 COGS instead of $8, because its terms and conditions say it is a platform company connecting drivers and riders.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate> <link>/accounting/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/accounting/</guid> <category>accounting</category> <category>startup</category> </item> <item> <title>Intellectual Property and Entrepreneurship</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes on Intellectual Property (IP) law for founders and busy professionals. Not legal advice. For informational purposes only. Laws can change, so this article may contain dated information. Always consult an attorney.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-big-4&quot;&gt;The big 4&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;patents&quot;&gt;Patents&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Patents protect novel, useful, non-obvious inventions. With full disclosure of the innovation, a patent grants the right to exclude others from making, using, selling, offering to sell, or importing the invention. It does not require its owner to use the patent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;Copyright&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Copyright protects original works of authorship fixed in any tangible medium of expression, such as source code, art (painting, photographs, acting), and sculpture.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Copyright does not protect functionality but only the expression. The author must independently create the work (no copying) and display some level of creativity. Copyright is secured automatically when the work is created.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Copyright owners have the exclusive right to create copyrightable derivative works, unless others obtain a licence from the owner. However, fair use is often a defense against infringement claims. Reverse engineering of competing products is fair use, but you can protect against reverse engineering using contracts. There are 4 factors to evaluate a fair use defense. Talk to your attorney.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;trademark&quot;&gt;Trademark&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;A trademark is a word/phrase/logo that identifies the source of goods. To register as a trademark the name of a well-known political figure and celebrity, their written consent is needed. Colors can be a trademark. Think Tiffany blue.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;trade-secrets&quot;&gt;Trade secrets&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trade secrets protect confidential company information that is commercially valuable and not publicly known, such as the Coca-Cola Coke formula. They do not require any registration with government agencies. Patent applications are considered trade secrets by the USPTO until their eventual publication.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The trade secret owner must have demonstrable intent to maintain confidentiality (use NDAs). Trade secrets can be licensed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;ideas-are-not-ip&quot;&gt;Ideas are not IP&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;IP law only protects the embodiment (expression, implementation) of ideas. Because ideas are not IP, they are not proprietary (i.e. cannot be owned), but they can be confidential (i.e. secrets).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, ideas may be protected with contracts, such as nondisclosure agreements (NDA) or payment agreements. California law might imply a contract in certain cases, but a contract will not be implied if the disclosure occurs before it is known that payment is a condition of use.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;nondisclosure-agreements&quot;&gt;Nondisclosure agreements&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Without an NDA, discussion of any invention is considered public disclosure, which prevents you from filing patents and voids your trade secrets. VCs do not sign NDAs. Hence, when pitching to VCs, 1) focus on the business and market, and 2) file a provisional patent application to lock in the priority date before talking to anyone who is not an inventor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like all agreements, an NDA must state the parties bounded by the agreement with date and signatures. It should identify the information discloser and receiver. It should describe with sufficient particularity the information to be disclosed. Saying that the NDA covers “everything provided” is likely to be not enforceable. The NDA should state the intended purpose and limitations of the use of the disclosed information (e.g. not a license to IP and cannot be used to develop any product). Make sure to mark confidential documents as such. Define the duration for disclosure exchange and for confidentiality preservation. Declare which state or country law governs the interpretation of the agreement.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Avoid the “residuals” provision, which says it is okay to use things remembered in memory.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;patents-1&quot;&gt;Patents&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Utility patents have a 20-year life from the application date and cannot be extended. Patents are granted to the first to file. Laws of nature (theorem, algorithm) and products of nature (animals) are not patentable. The patent owners, not the government, police their patent rights.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A provisional application is recommended not only because it secures an earlier priority date but also because filing patents is expensive (thousands of dollars before lawyer fee) and time-consuming (takes about 25 months to issue), so the 1-year grace period allows the inventor to evaluate the business strategy to decide if patent filing is worth it. Patent protection does not start until the patent issues.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A patent requires the invention to be novel. An invention is not novel if it is anticipated (identical to a prior art). Public disclosures—talking to noninventors, publication, selling, offering to sell—count as prior art. So again, NDAs and provisional applications are recommended.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;That which will infringe, if later, will anticipate, if earlier.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Peters v. Active Mfg.&lt;/em&gt;, 21 F. 319&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Patents are always issued on Tuesday. Why? Because the USPTO said so.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Patent claims must be written in one sentence. Why? Because the USPTO said so.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A patent licensee may challenge the patent (e.g. that it was anticipated) while retaining a licence to the patent. If you lose the patent challenge, you still have the licence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;AI cannot be an inventor, who must a human being.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;employment-agreements&quot;&gt;Employment agreements&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;An employment agreement likely includes an IP assignment agreement, meaning IP created within the scope of employment is owned by the employer. The employer owns the code written by its engineers, but not the code written by janitors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Always include such assignment agreement, essentially for contractors. Do not use the phrase “work made for hire”, which in California makes a contractor an employee. The assignment agreement will protect the company in case some employees leave and start their own thing using the same IP.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;california-safe-harbor&quot;&gt;California safe harbor&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;The assignment agreement with the employer does not apply to inventions an employee developed entirely on their own time without using the employer’s equipment, supplies, facilities, or trade secret. However, exceptions are&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;(1) Relate at the time of conception or reduction to practice of the invention to the employer’s business, or actual or demonstrably anticipated research or development of the employer; or&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;(2) Result from any work performed by the employee for the employer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– California labor code section 2870 (a)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is always a peril when someone is still employed elsewhere while also working on the startup. This person probably also signed IP assignment agreement with that other employer, and exception (2) above makes things really tricky.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ideally, have a clean cut. Quit former employer, start the company, then develop. This issue always comes up during due diligence when you raise funding or seek exits.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;ownership-and-multiple-creators&quot;&gt;Ownership and multiple creators&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;For every type of IP, the default owner is the creators:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;patents: inventors&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;copyrights: authors&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;trademark: first user in commerce&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;trade secrets: creators&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;The legal default is that creators are the joint owners of equal rights regardless of the disparity in contribution. Equal ownership can only be shifted by assignment agreements.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Among co-owners, licensing rights are often the most contentious. To avoid disputes, one option is to divide up the right so that each owner will have exclusive rights to grant licenses only in a particular industry or country.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In community property states, such as California, spouses have ownership rights in IP created by the other spouse during the term of the marriage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As shown below, there are unique ownership issues for different types of IP.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;patents-2&quot;&gt;Patents&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Absent written agreement, all inventors can each independently license to third parties without any duty or notice to co-inventors, perhaps with inconsistent terms. Hence, co-owners could compete with each other.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;copyrights&quot;&gt;Copyrights&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Absent written agreement, each owner can independently license to third parties on inconsistent terms, but contrary to patent law, all co-owners have a duty to each other to provide financial accounting and share the proceeds from licensing. Such duty can be changed with written agreements.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;trademarks&quot;&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is the business, not the creators that own the trademark. The artistic appearance of the trademark might be protected by copyright. Do not use the logo unless the copyright is assigned or licensed to the company, especially when the logo is produced by a contractor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;open-source-software-oss-licensing&quot;&gt;Open-source software (OSS) licensing&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The following 6 OSS licenses cover 99% of the use case.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copy-left licenses (free software)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;GPL&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;LGPL&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Eclipse Public License, CDDL, Mozilla Public License (these 3 are effectively identical)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permissive licenses&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;BSD&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;MIT&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Apache 2&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Permissive licenses allow the user to do whatever as long as the license header is kept.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Copy-left licenses require that if you distribute your software in binary form, you must make the corresponding source code available to binary recipients and only license your code on the same copy-left licensing terms.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Distribution is the key here because it is a right under the US copyright law. Distribution means transferring a copy from a legal person to another. Absent distribution, most OSS licenses impose no condition. For most licenses, SaaS is not considered distribution, but pay attention to the recent trend of adoption of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server_Side_Public_License&quot;&gt;Server Side Public License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Copy-left licenses have different levels of restriction as shown below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;gpl---strong-copyleft&quot;&gt;GPL - strong copyleft&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;if any code in a program is GPL, it must all be GPL. This means no proprietary code in a GPL codebase and no linking to proprietary code, because linking is a process that creates executables, as opposed to ways of inter-process communication. In a GPL codebase, code may come from other GPL compatible licenses, such as permissive licenses.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Everything in kernel space is GPL. Proprietary code in the kernel space is risky. Application code that communicates with the kernel through syscalls can be proprietary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;lgpl---library-copyleft&quot;&gt;LGPL - library copyleft&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;If any code in a library is LGPL, then the entire library is LGPL. However, you can dynamically link to proprietary code, which means you need to share changes to the library but not the code using the library. Static linking to proprietary code might be permitted but most companies decided not to after talking to their attorneys. Note that scripting languages basically work by the equivalent of dynamic linking for the purpose of this analysis.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;mozilla-eclipse-cddl---weak-copyleft&quot;&gt;Mozilla, Eclipse, CDDL - weak copyleft&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;With no rules about linking, these licenses are friendly to proprietary code, which should be kept in a separate file. If you did not modify the licensed code, you easily comply. If you did modify, a simple legal review can help you comply.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate> <link>/ip-law/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/ip-law/</guid> <category>law</category> <category>startup</category> </item> <item> <title>Life and Investment Through the Lens of Uncertainty</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: Opinions are my own. Not investment advice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;decisions-are-not-judged-by-results&quot;&gt;Decisions are not judged by results&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Decisions and results are separate. The quality of a decision should not be judged by the quality of its result, which often depends on randomness.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If I drove drunk yet got home safely, I have made a bad decision with a good outcome. If I drove sober and careful but was rear-ended, I have made a good decision with a bad outcome.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If I rushed into $NIO upon open, dumped before close, and netted some decent gain, did I make a good decision? So much of one’s success was attributed to the research and painstaking, often confusing luck with skills, and signal with noise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the last 20 years, $SPY has a nontrivial mean daily return of 0.0338% but a standard deviation of 1.2405%, which is 37 times the return. Holding it for just a day is really speculating as opposed to investing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We always make decisions under uncertainty, but our weapons are legions—probability, expectation, and Monte Carlo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;vanish-of-randomness&quot;&gt;Vanish of randomness&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Suppose we treat each daily return &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;R1, R2, ..., Rn&lt;/code&gt; as a random variable from the same distribution—any distribution, especially not Normal. Suppose the distribution has a mean &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mu&lt;/code&gt; and standard deviation &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sigma&lt;/code&gt;. Then, the sum of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;R1, R2, ..., Rn&lt;/code&gt; has mean &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n * mu&lt;/code&gt; and and standard deviation &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sqrt(n) * sigma&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In layman’s terms, the longer you hold a stock, the narrower the distribution of its return. If you end up with a spike, it means you almost always make money.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This analysis is simplified and assumes the underlying distribution does not change. The real distribution is not observable, but with so many pension and retirement funds in the market, your investment positions are also a reflection of your confidence in the federal government.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;uncertainty-has-existed-in-the-past&quot;&gt;Uncertainty has existed in the past&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Uncertainty implies unknown and seems applicable only to future events. After all, I cannot predict the tomorrow price of a stock, but I know for sure what its price was yesterday. The past can only be learned but not altered.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yet uncertainty has existed in the past. The price went up yesterday, but it &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have gone down. Be very careful with past observations. What has happened is only one of the possibilities. Watch out for the “alternative” histories, cried &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nassim_Nicholas_Taleb&quot;&gt;Nassim Nicholas Taleb&lt;/a&gt;. If a certain kind of events—no one has seen a black swan, or the market has never gone down more than 20% in a day—has never been observed before, we cannot conclude it is impossible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;stay-in-the-game&quot;&gt;Stay in the game&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The black swan is not scary as long as you can keep playing. Stay away from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_roulette&quot;&gt;Russian roulette&lt;/a&gt;. No matter how lucrative the upside is, there is no come back if you get wiped out. Limit tail risk. Always fasten the seat belt.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;know-your-tools&quot;&gt;Know your tools&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Through what instruments, you asked. It is like choosing the tech stack for your startup: always the ones you know.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Call options have the leverage and convexity that bends in your favor regardless of the price going up or down, or so you have overheard in an anonymous web forum. Not entirely in apropos, but at what cost? What if the price remains stationary? Hint: look into &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greeks_(finance)#Theta&quot;&gt;theta&lt;/a&gt; risk.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;being-reasonable-not-rational&quot;&gt;Being reasonable, not rational&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is never about achieving the most optimal return, but a good enough one that allows me to sleep at night and achieves my life goals. Investing is a means to an end. Be patient and start living.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Warren Buffett’s skill is investing, but his secret is time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Morgan Housel, The Psychology of Money&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; </description> <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate> <link>/uncertain/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/uncertain/</guid> <category>investment</category> <category>career</category> </item> <item> <title>Navigating Shell for Productivity and Profit</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope you find inspirations from these pretty neat shell tricks and my shell setup.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;array-expansion&quot;&gt;Array Expansion&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Use Array Expansion to quickly build arguments to a command. For example, to download several HTTP resources:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;$ wget https://kubernetespodcast.com/episodes/KPfGep{001..062}.mp3 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;To rename files when you just want to change a substring.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;$ mv /path/to/same-prefix-{old,new}.txt &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;process-substitution-and-anonymous-files&quot;&gt;Process Substitution and Anonymous Files&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;()&lt;/code&gt; redirects the stdout of the command in the subshell to a file descriptor opened at &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/dev/fd&lt;/code&gt;. This is known as process substitution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;$ sh &amp;lt;(curl -sL https://istio.io/downloadIstioctl) &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;The above is equivalent to the following, where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; means to use the stdin as a file.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;$ curl -sL https://istio.io/downloadIstioctl | sh - &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note that process substitution is more powerful than pipes, since you can do things like&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;$ diff &amp;lt;(ssh somehost cat /etc/hosts) &amp;lt;(ssh some-other-host cat /etc/hosts) &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;start-new-shell&quot;&gt;Start new shell&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Just updated your bashrc/zshrc file, but want to hold on to your environment variables, file descriptors, etc? Do this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;$ exec -l $SHELL &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-password-is-sudo&quot;&gt;The password is sudo&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dealing with production outage and in dire need of mitigation?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;$ sudo su &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;And then you are always the root master. “I don’t test in prod; I dev in prod.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;alias-for-the-win&quot;&gt;Alias for the Win&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Type less. Move fast. Here are some I use everyday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;mcd&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;mkdir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-p&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; cdl&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;ls&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;alias ls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;ls -F -G&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;alias &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;ll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;ls -lh&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;alias &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;open&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;alias &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;ping&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;ping -c 5&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;alias &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;gauth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;gcloud auth login --update-adc&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;(I consider it a work injury that I now quote everything in shell and has long stopped using white space in file names even for personal stuff. Maybe you are like me.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;cursor-navigation&quot;&gt;Cursor Navigation&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/shell/1.png&quot; width=&quot;1680&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;command-deletion&quot;&gt;Command Deletion&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/shell/2.png&quot; width=&quot;1680&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;in-line-file&quot;&gt;In-line file&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cat&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;EOF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sh&quot;&gt; | kubectl create -f - apiVersion: v1 kind: Pod metadata: name: nginx spec: containers: - name: nginx image: nginx &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;EOF &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;search-command-history-with-fuzzy-find&quot;&gt;Search Command History with Fuzzy Find&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;You probably know you could use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ctrl+r&lt;/code&gt; to retrieve a previously executed command quickly, but it only gives you one suggestion. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/junegunn/fzf&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fzf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; solves it not only for commands but finds files as well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/shell/3.png&quot; width=&quot;1680&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;auto-correct-command-typos&quot;&gt;Auto-correct Command Typos&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I don’t endorse profanity but we all share the frustration. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nvbn/thefuck&quot;&gt;Thefuck&lt;/a&gt; will correct your mistake.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/shell/4.gif&quot; width=&quot;1680&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;zsh-ohmyzsh-and-powerlevel10k&quot;&gt;ZSH, ohmyzsh, and powerlevel10k&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;ZSH, or Z shell, is an extended version of the Bourne Shell (sh), with numerous new features, plugins, and themes. To change your shell to ZSH&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;$ chsh -s $(which zsh) &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ohmyzsh/ohmyzsh&quot;&gt;Ohmyzsh&lt;/a&gt; is a plugin manager for ZSH. I recommend at least two plugins.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zsh-users/zsh-autosuggestions&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;autosuggestions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; makes zsh like fish.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/shell/5.png&quot; width=&quot;1680&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zsh-users/zsh-syntax-highlighting&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;syntax-highlighting&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; colorizes the command and strings, providing visual warning for typos.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/shell/6.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; </description> <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate> <link>/shell/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/shell/</guid> <category>shell</category> </item> <item> <title>Software Engineering Levels and Promotion</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;This post explains the expectation of each engineering level in the most concise and company-agnostic way and reveals the steps towards promotion.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;levels&quot;&gt;Levels&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first step to prepare for promotion is to understand the expectation of each level. Having worked at several companies ranging from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/f/faang-stocks.asp&quot;&gt;FAANG&lt;/a&gt; to startups in the valley, I noticed that the engineering leveling systems are awfully similar.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;new-grad--entry-level-l3&quot;&gt;New grad / Entry-level (L3)&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Deliver assigned tasks timely and independently&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;software-engineer-l4&quot;&gt;Software Engineer (L4)&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Design, implement, and operate scalable systems for well-scoped projects&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;senior-engineer-l5&quot;&gt;Senior Engineer (L5)&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Define and scope undefined problems given defined goals&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Substantial impact within the team &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Mentoring junior engineers&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Technical oversight&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;staff-engineer-l6&quot;&gt;Staff Engineer (L6)&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Propose and drive cross-functional initiatives, define goals, identify and connect stakeholders&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;senior-staff-engineer--principal-engineer-l7&quot;&gt;Senior Staff Engineer / Principal Engineer (L7+)&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;It becomes stratospheric from here. Engineers at such levels are experts in their domains.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Invent and evangelize new products and technologies&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;promotions&quot;&gt;Promotions&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are many moving pieces when you work towards a promo. If you forget everything I shared in this post, try to remember this: the single most important thing to do for a promo is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;consistently delivering projects at the next level of scope&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is also one of the reasons (besides budgeting) why promotion is getting slower and harder to come by at some of FAANG, because with the money-printing success of the company’s business model, development work gradually shifts towards keeping the lights on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Below are generic steps towards a promotion.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;step-1-reasonable-manager&quot;&gt;Step 1: Reasonable manager&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;The promotion process, as well as one’s life, depends more or less on luck on getting the right manager and projects. Without a supportive manager, promotion is rather difficult, because your manager is the person who represents you in the calibration and promo committee review.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At least, your manager should view people development as part of her job and believe that you have the potential to grow into the next level. If you unfortunately end up in some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.susanjfowler.com/blog/2017/2/19/reflecting-on-one-very-strange-year-at-uber&quot;&gt;toxic&lt;/a&gt; work environment, there are ways to get promo too that I do not recommend. Instead, my suggestion in this case would be to run away screaming (change team or company).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2-identify-gaps&quot;&gt;Step 2: Identify gaps&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Engage with your manager in your &lt;a href=&quot;/one-on-one&quot;&gt;weekly one on one&lt;/a&gt;, to share your career aspiration and together identify the gaps between your current and the next level. Two things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seek actionable feedback.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are L3 and your manager says the tasks you have delivered are not technically challenging enough, this feedback probably is not actionable for you, because you are likely not the person deciding on which tasks to focus on. An example of actionable feedback is to “be more vocal about your opinions by speaking up more in meetings and commenting on design docs”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perception is reality.&lt;/strong&gt; If your manager thinks you have a communication problem, then you need to solve this communication problem to get promo. You may disagree with such diagnosis, or there might be underlying causes for such a symptom, but your manager’s perception is what matters here.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;step-3-find-the-right-projects&quot;&gt;Step 3: Find the right projects&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;To repeat from the opening of this section, the key to promotion is to deliver projects at the next level of impact.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At L3/4, finding such projects are easy. Most projects permit designs that go on an extra mile in terms of feature, scalability, testability, and operational excellence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At L5 and beyond, it gets a bit tricky. Most teams do not have a backlog of L6 projects, which is one of the reasons why many plateau at L5. So again, luck (right place and the right time) is needed for promo. Your manager and maybe tech lead are responsible for prioritization and project scoping. Make sure to loop them in to strategize for these projects.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;step-4-learn-and-grow&quot;&gt;Step 4: Learn and grow&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Learn all the new technologies. Build healthy relationships with sister teams. Execute on the projects. Establish competencies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;step-5-demonstrate-impact&quot;&gt;Step 5: Demonstrate impact&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;You may believe in meritocracy and think the excellence of your work warrants attention and rewards, or perhaps you are being humble. Yet the reality is that most people are too busy to look if you do not point them in your direction.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bombast about yourself feels awkward and might backfire. The trick is to let other people praise you, especially those who are at high levels than your target level. Relationship is important not only because it may unblock your project dependencies but also because many, after all, judge books by covers and believe trusts are transitive.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Prefer written evidence if you can, such as design docs you authored, video recording of your demo at all-hands, and thank you notes / peer bonus.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Following these steps and with sustained performance at the next level, promotion is yours. If not, did I mention luck and having a reasonable manager? My run-away-screaming advice still holds.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate> <link>/promo/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/promo/</guid> <category>career</category> </item> <item> <title>What to Talk about in Effective 1-on-1s</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike in school when we get grades on every assignment and in every course, we get less frequent feedback in professional life, usually once or twice per year, which is also when compensation and level adjustment happens.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The infrequent feedback might be frustrating, since it introduces artificial delays in recognizing and acting on improvement opportunities. Careers management is not so different from product management—fast iterations of small improvements are the proven route towards success.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One-on-one meetings allow a much smaller feedback cycle. You should schedule regular one-on-ones with your direct manager, if not your skip manager as well. However, it is not trivial to run effective one-on-ones. Sometimes they become status updates or are simply skipped over (Pro tip: don’t cancel but reschedule instead). Just like you own your career, you also own the one-on-ones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are some good questions to ask your manager or share your answers with your manager.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;what-to-talk-about&quot;&gt;What to talk about&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this context, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;you&lt;/code&gt; means the manager and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;I&lt;/code&gt; represents the individual contributor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;career-and-performance&quot;&gt;Career and Performance&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;how-am-i-meeting-your-expectation&quot;&gt;How am I meeting your expectation?&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;p&gt;Could you help me understand what the expectations of me are at my current level? What does “Exceeds Expectation” rating mean in the context of our team? From what you have seen in calibration and performance review, what are the set of projects and impacts I should aim for to reach such a rating?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;what-is-my-next-career-goal-could-you-help-me-identify-the-specific-gaps-between-where-i-am-and-my-goal-what-are-the-and-action-items-to-bridge-the-gap&quot;&gt;What is my next career goal? Could you help me identify the specific gaps between where I am and my goal? What are the and action items to bridge the gap?&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;To grow into a senior/staff engineer or an engineering manager requires different skills and experience. You want your manager to know your aspiration and together devise a plan to achieve it. How can the manager be helpful without knowing what you want?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Whose job do I want in the future? Do I know what their functions are?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;team-and-satisfaction&quot;&gt;Team and Satisfaction&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;am-i-happy-with-the-projects-i-am-working-on&quot;&gt;Am I happy with the projects I am working on?&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Is it too much operation than development? Am I learning new skills? Can I accomplish my tasks? &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;An ideal job/project should mandate a level of expertise of which I satisfy 60%. Anything more will be trivial to solve and not enough growth for me, but anything less will be overwhelming and set me up for failure.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Are these projects meaningful or impactful?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;I am very excited about the XYZ project that Jane Doe is working on. She would be a great mentor for me and XYZ is a top priority of our team. How can I contribute? Would you be supportive of me to involve in that project for my career development?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;am-i-happy-on-this-team&quot;&gt;Am I happy on this team?&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;p&gt;Are my peers capable of delivering results? Do they have a strong personality that makes it hard to work with them sometimes? Do they write awesome reviews on my pull requests, or am I tired of their nit-picking?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;am-i-happy-with-my-manager&quot;&gt;Am I happy with my manager?&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do I get the support I need? Does my manager maintain a healthy cross-functional relationship? Do I wish my manager to lean more toward technical leadership or people management?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h5 id=&quot;am-i-happy-at-this-company&quot;&gt;Am I happy at this company?&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;p&gt;Are there certain policies I like or dislike? Do I enjoy the culture? Do I trust senior leadership?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;projects-and-processes&quot;&gt;Projects and Processes&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Instead of providing status updates, ask: Do you feel we have a strong tracking process to keep you updated on the project status?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Are we setting realistic goals? Do you like our quarterly/sprint planning process?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; </description> <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate> <link>/one-on-one/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">/one-on-one/</guid> <category>career</category> </item> </channel> </rss>